准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
珊迪的火箭
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
嘿  珊迪
Hey, Sandy
你好啊  海绵宝宝
Howdy, SpongeBob
觉得这个怎么样
How do you like it?
这是什么
What is it?
是火箭飞船  这都不知道
It's a rocket ship, duh
我们下面见  给你到里面逛逛
I'll meet you downstairs and show you around
你要用它来干什么
What are you going to do with it?
月球
我要去月球  海绵宝宝
I'm going to the moon, SpongeBob
月球
The moon
我可以去吗
Can I go?
不行  海绵宝宝
No way, SpongeBob
特别是自从你弄坏了我直升机以后
especially after your little mishap
with my whirlybird
逝者安息
再说你也坐不下
Besides, there's not enough room for you
可我占不了多大地方的
But I don't take up that much space
看到没
See?
我塞得进去
I can fit in here
舒服
Cozy
这抽屉我要用
I need that drawer
那么这样呢
Well, how about this
这样呢
or this
or this?
海绵宝宝  这可不是闹着玩
SpongeBob, this isn't for fun--
看到这个了吗
See this?
这是科学
This is science
我没时间嬉耍打闹
I don't have time for fun and games
也没时间处理偷渡分子
and I don't have time for stowaways
好吧
Fine
那就把我关进禁闭室里
Put me in the brig
我不会介意的
I don't mind
那是通风口  海绵宝宝
That's the air bed, SpongeBob
这我也要用
I need that, too
求你了  我可以去吗
Oh, please, can I go?
可以吗
Can I
求你了
Please?
好吧
All right
你可以待在货舱里  只要你
y'all can ride in the cargo hold if you just
好耶
Yeah
去月球
Going to the moon
月球旅行
Moonride
不过这回
But this time
什么都不要碰  好吗
just don't touch anything, okay?
看看这气枪
Look at that popgun
我们是要去月球抓外星人吗
Are we going to go hunting aliens on the moon?
别吵  傻瓜
Oh, hush, silly
这是用来采集月球岩石的
This is for harvesting moon rocks
等你石头玩够了
When you're done playing with rocks
也可以用那玩意来抓外星人
you could use that for some serious alien hunting
外星人
Aliens?
你是不是傻
Are you nuts?
我去过月球
I've been to the moon
根本没有外星人
There are no aliens
珊迪
Sandy
你怎么能这么幼稚
How can you be so naive?
周围到处都是证据
There's evidence all around us
你要怎么解释亚特兰蒂斯
How do you explain Atlantis
翘头发
cowlicks
99分商店
99-cent stores?
还有怎么解释海草田里
And how about those mysterious circles
一夜之间冒出来的怪圈
that pop up in kelp fields overnight?
这就有一个
There's one now
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你对太空一窍不通
you don't know the first thing about outer space
现在快回家睡觉去吧
Now go home and get some shuteye
明天一早就过来这里
Be here tomorrow at the crack of dawn
别老是想什么外星人了
and leave your crazy alien notions behind
小蜗
快点
Hurry up
这样应该就成了
This ought to do the trick
你好  海绵宝宝
Hiya, SpongeBob
怎么了  派大星
What is it, Patrick?
没看出来我在睡觉吗
Can't you see I'm sleeping here?
我听说你明天就要去月球旅行了
Well, I know you're going on that moon trip tomorrow
我想给你带份东西
and I just wanted to bring you something
礼物吗
A present?
不对
No
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
珊迪的火箭能防外星人吗
Is Sandy's rocket alien-proof?
根本没有外星人  派大星
There are no aliens, Patrick
不信问珊迪
Just ask Sandy
那看来你就用不着
Well, I guess you won't be needing
去月球时带上这个防外星人喷雾了
this alien repellent for your trip
防外星人喷雾
Alien repellent?
让我看看
Let me see that
驱外星人
全新款驱外星人
"New alien-out
窗户防护
"Window Protectant
无法防小偷
"Does not stop burglars"
看来你说得对  派大星
Well, I guess you're right, Patrick
最好去给窗户都喷一下
We better go spray those windows
看看它有多大  海绵宝宝
Look how big it is, SpongeBob
非常厉害  没错
It's pretty impressive, all right
快来
Come on
我们只是来这喷窗户的  派大星
We're just here to spray the windows, Patrick
开
你说要怎样才能进去
How do you think we get inside?
不行
We don't
我们只是来这喷
We're just spraying the
窗户的
windows
我打开了  海绵宝宝
I opened it, SpongeBob
快来
Come on
我的天啊  海绵宝宝
Holy sea cow, SpongeBob
这肯定就是控制室了
This must be the control room
对  什么都不要乱碰
Yeah, just don't touch anything
快看  我要赢了
Look, I'm winning
派大星  别闹了
Patrick, cut that out
派大星  快点
Patrick, come on
不能在里面到处乱晃
We can't hang around in here
这可是珊迪的大火箭
This is Sandy's big rocket
不是什么游乐园
not some kind of fun house
赢了
Winner
耶  高分
Yeah, high score
派大星  话说那是什么游戏来着
Hey, Patrick, what game was that, anyway?
不知道  不过来看看这是干什么的
I don't know, but let's see what this does
派大星  好像不该
Patrick, I don't think we should
我好喜欢火箭
I like rockets
再来  再来
More, more
不要再来了
No more
好  再来一遍
Okay, one more
差不多得了
Okay, that's enough
走了
Let's go
等等  这个好像可以启动火箭
Wait, I think this one starts it
派大星  你在干什么
Patrick, what are you doing?
去太空旅行的是我
I'm the space traveler here
我刚好知道
and I happen to know that
那个启动按钮就在这
that particular button is right over here
我们启动火箭了
We've started the rocket
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
撑住  兄弟
Hang on, buddy
我们不坠落了
We stopped falling
你看  我们上太空了
Look, we're in space now
谁来拉我下来上去之类的
Somebody get me down or up, or something
海绵宝宝  瞧好了
Hey, SpongeBob, watch this
你把牙膏挤到我花生酱里了
You got your toothpaste in my peanut butter
派大星  我可以这样
Patrick, I can do this
谁又把重力打开了
Who turned the heavy back on?
我们肯定要着陆了
We must be landing
好耶
All right
有时候海绵宝宝就是傻得要命
Sometimes that SpongeBob
is as dumb as a sack of peanuts
看起来跟家好像
It sure looks a lot like home
快看  是小蜗
Hey, look, it's Gary
过来  小蜗小蜗
Come here, Gary, Gary
慢着
Wait
不要靠近它  派大星
Don't go near him, Patrick
看不出来这都是诡计吗
Can't you see this is all a trick?
外星人在把我们的记忆投射到环境里
The aliens are projecting our memories
onto the environment
是要迷惑我们  派大星
They're trying to confuse us, Patrick
所以你是想说
So you mean to say
他们取出了我们想的想法
they've taken what we thought we think
让我们想
and make us think
我们一直在想的
we thought our thoughts we've been thinking
我们想的想法的想法
our thoughts we think we thought?
心里想的
We think?
好  我是不会上当的
Okay, but I'm not going to fall for it
好
Yeah
抓到它了  海绵宝宝
You got him, SpongeBob
珊迪会不会很骄傲
Won't Sandy be proud?
珊迪
Sandy
我都忘了她了
I forgot all about her
我们偷她火箭  她会讨厌我们的
She's going to hate us for stealing her rocket
但等我把外星人带给她
But won't she feel silly
她会不会觉得自己傻呢
when I bring her back a real live alien?
她会爱上我的
She'll love me
快点  派大星
Come on, Patrick
人多力量大
The more the merrier
抓外星人
Alien hunting
嘘  派大星
Shh, Patrick
别暴露抓他们的动机
don't let them know we're on to them
对  抓外星人
Yeah, alien hunting--
我也在电视上看到过
I saw that on TV, too
派大星  顺便来看下老朋友章鱼哥
Patrick, let's drop in on our old pal Squidward
看看他想干什么
and see what he's up to
确保气枪的气打好了
Make sure your gun is pumped
看啊  派大星
Look at it, Patrick
太恶心了
It's disgusting
奶奶
Grandma
凑近看更丑了
It's even uglier up close
开始分析吧
Let's begin the analysis
等等
Wait
那是什么
What's that?
我觉得我快要吐了
I think I'm going to be sick
派大星  你知道这是什么吗
Patrick, do you know what this thing is?
臭臭
Stinky
不对  是卵囊
No, it's an egg sac
来看看胚胎
Let's look at the embryo
双胞胎
Twins
抱歉用语不当
Pardon my French
把这东西从我身上弄下去
but get this thing off me
派大星和海绵宝宝
Patrick and SpongeBob
滚出我的卧室
get out of my bedroom
放下我的爪子
and give me back my tentacles
它醒了
It's awake
来抓住这个小骗子吧
Let's capture the little phony
离我远点
Get away from me
你们好啊  小子
Ahoy, there, lads
现在扮海盗是不是有点晚了
Up a bit late to be playing pirate, aren't ye?
等等  别开枪
Wait, don't shoot
好吧好吧  开枪吧
Okay, okay, shoot me
可是别拿走我的钱
but don't take me money
我们不想要你的钱  月球人
We don't want your money, moon man
看他们在里面蠕动的样子
Look at them squirming around in there
恶心
Gross
外星人还有很多呢
Well, plenty more where those came from
滑浪学校
海绵宝宝  这么晚来这干什么
SpongeBob, what are you doing here so late?
不管这是干什么
Whatever this is
全都要记在你档案里
it's going on your permanent record
太可笑了
This is ridiculous
快放我出去
Please let me out of here
海绵宝宝  我觉得可能要再跑一趟
SpongeBob, I think we might have to make a second trip
没时间搞那个
There's no time for that--
用力推
just push harder
海绵宝宝  你们在搞什么鬼
SpongeBob, what are y'all doing?
我放任你们两秒钟不管
I can't turn my back on you for two seconds
你们就闯了一大堆的祸
without you causing a whole mess of trouble
看看你们
Well, look at you
把你朋友跟邻居全塞袋子里
bagging up all your friends and neighbors
就好像有新鲜的山核桃熏香肠似的
just like there was a fresh crop
of hickory-smoked sausages
你们把我的科学小实验搞砸了
You done turned my little science experiment
into a disaster
你们应该为自己感到羞耻
You two ought to be ashamed of yourself
别骗人了  珊迪
Nice try, Sandy
或者该不该说是  外星小姐
Or should I say, miss alien pants?
外星人
Aliens?
这就是你们的目的
Is that what this is about?
这不是月球
This isn't the moon
我们还在裤头
We're still in Bikini Bo --
就跟你说  谁都不能相信
Just goes to show you, you can't trust anyone
所以你一直都是个外星人
So, you were an alien all the time
而你却从来不告诉我
and you didn't even tell me
我从来都不知道
I didn't even know
是吗
Yeah?
那我该抓你了
Well, I got you now
你是抓不到我的  只有
But it's not you that's got me, it's
我抓我自己
Me that's got me
天啊  等不及要看到珊迪的表情了
Boy, I can't wait to see the look on Sandy's face
珊迪  我回来了
Sandy, I'm back
裤头村看着好不一样
Bikini Bottom sure looks different
海绵宝宝  我们外星人想跟你说句话
SpongeBob, we aliens would like a word with you
吱吱叫的靴子
分镜总监
分镜
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
珍珍是我女儿  我要烦死你
Pearl is my daughter, I'll spit in your eye
珍珍是头鲸鱼  今天是她生日
Pearl's a whale, and it's her birthday
谢谢你的表演  老爸
Thanks for the show, dad
现在能开礼物了吗
Now can we open the presents?
好啊
All right
给我亲爱的小沙丁鱼的礼物
Presents for me darling little sardine
拿去
There you are
不用这样的
You shouldn't have
是什么  老爸
What is it, daddy?
该不会是我朋友都在穿的
It wouldn't be those totally hip new flipper slippers
全新脚蹼鞋吧
all my friends are wearing
大家都可想要了
Everyone wants them
应该是
It might be
不用这样
You shouldn't have
用不着这样
我是说  爸
I mean, dad
你就用不着送这礼物
You really shouldn't have
珍珍  这双可是全场最好的钓鱼靴
Pearl, those are the finest fishing boots available
爸  你毁了我
Dad, you ruined me
我可是砍价买的
But I got them for a bargain
蟹堡王
我该怎么办
What am I going to do?
我整整花了两块钱买了这靴子
I spent two whole dollars on these boots
现在这玩意甩不开了
and now I'm stuck with them
蟹老板  我能领工资吗
Mr. Krabs, can I get my paycheck?
海绵宝宝
Spongeboy-me-bob
请进请进
Come in, come in
到这来  小子
Right this way, laddie
坐哪都行
Have a seat anywhere
就是别坐上这双美丽无价的靴子
but not on these beautiful, priceless boots
所以你想领工资
So you want your pay
老板  我看不到你
Sir, I can't see you
靴子
The boots
挡住了
are in
视线
the way
挡视线
In the way?
这双靴子从来就没离开过我的视线
These boots never leave my sight
这可是我手上既昂贵又珍贵的宝贝
These are the most expensive
and prized possessions I own
真的吗
Really?
为什么呢
Why is that?
这靴子跟一般的靴子没区别
They look just like any old ordinary boots
一般的靴子
Ordinary boots?
这可是绝无仅有的正式煎炸厨师靴
These are the only official fry cook boots
只有全世界最好的煎炸厨师
Only the finest fry cooks in the world
才可以穿上  这是传统
are permitted to wear them, part of a tradition
我这双靴子是
And these boots were given to me
一位海底最有名的煎炸厨师给的
by the most famous fry cook in the sea
谁啊
Who's that?
他是谁不重要
Well, his name is not important
反正他很有名
But he was famous
好了  别管那么多
All right, don't you worry
我准备好了
I'm ready
我要靴子
I want those boots
抱歉小子  这靴子实在太珍贵了
Sorry, son, these boots are far too valuable
有了
I know
要是我拿蟹堡王的工资抵怎么样
What if I give you my Krusty Krab paycheck?
工资
Paycheck
成交
You got a deal
要是我免费粉刷蟹堡王怎么样
And what if I paint the Krusty Krab for free?
成交
You got a deal
我还要免费送够一年用的薯条油
And I'll throw in a year's supply of French fry oil
成
You got
先等一下  小子
Hold on there, lad
你要害我心脏病发作了
You're going to give me a heart attack
全都成交
You got yourself a deal
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
喜欢我的新靴子吗
Do you like my new boots?
是不是很酷
Pretty cool, huh?
现在我是正式煎炸厨师了
Now I'm an official fry cook
吱吱叫的声音要害我疯掉了
That squeaking is going to drive us all crazy
胡说八道  章鱼哥
Nonsense, Squidward
吱吱叫的声音在我听来就是钱
That squeaking is money to my ears
我是说  音乐
I mean, music
钱
Money
十
Ten
二十
Twenty
三十
Thirty
四十
Forty
什么
Wha
谁在那
Who's there?
继续数钱
Back to counting me money
一
One
二
Two
三
Three
四
Four
五
Five
那到底是什么玩意
What the barnacle is that, huh?
小心点
Careful
昨晚是我度过的最难熬的一晚了
That was the worst night I ever weathered
蟹堡王
至少我上班还能享受清静
At least I'll have some peace and quiet at work
听好了  蟹老板
Watch it, Mr. Krabs
我要度我的假去了
I'm taking my vacation now
怎么回事  章鱼哥先生
What's wrong, Mr. Squidward?
我再也受不了世界最好煎炸厨师了
I can't take the world's greatest fry cook anymore
一星期后再见
I'll see you in a week
那煎炸厨师在帮我发大财
That fry cook is making me a fortune
会有什么问题
What could be the problem?
嘿  蟹老板
Hey, Mr. Krabs
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
宝宝
Bob
我
I, uh
看到你还在穿这双靴子
see you're still wearing them boots
你开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
我可喜欢了
I love them
全世界最好的厨师能这样吗
Could the world's greatest fry cook do this?
那个
Well, uh
我不
I don't, uh
他还会不会这样
Or could he do this?
还是这样
Or this?
此处点餐
瞧好了  蟹老板
And watch this, Mr. Krabs
我能为你点餐吗
Can I take your order?
好  我要来份蟹堡特餐
Yeah, I'll have the Krusty special
谢谢先生
Thank you, sir
做好我会吱一声的
I will squeak when it's ready
最好的厨师能这样吗  蟹老板
Could the greatest fry cook do that, Mr. Krabs?
我
I, uh
看这个  蟹老板
And look at this, Mr. Krabs
还有这个
And this
我得去办公室一趟
I got to go to my office
我还是听得到
I can still hear it
还是能透过来
It's still coming through
可恶的吱吱叫
The infernal squeak
这靴子必须消失
Those boots have got to go
我要来片阿司匹林
And I need an aspirin
小蜗  这双靴子改变了我的一生
Gary, these boots have changed my life
小蜗
我再也不脱掉了
I'm never taking them off
晚安  小蜗
Good night, Gary
蟹堡王
安静的钱
Quiet money
既有宁静又有钱
Silence and money
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
怎么了  我的小子
What is it, my boy?
蟹老板  我好对不起
Mr. Krabs, I'm sorry
对不起对不起
Sorry, sorry
我好对不起
I'm sorry
没事的  小子
It's okay, son
不对  很有事
No, it's not okay
我把靴子丢了
I lost the boots
你珍贵的靴子
your valuable boots
都是我的错
It's my fault
我让你失望了
I let you down
我好对不起
I'm sorry
对不起
Sorry
别哭  小子
Hold it, boy
这又不是世界末日
It's not the end of the world
这就是
Yes, it is
听好  别哭了
Look, don't cry
我有双
I've got some, uh
有双神奇烤箱手套
Some magic oven mitts
那又不一样
They're not the same
你说得对
You were right--
我还不配穿上那双神圣靴子
I wasn't ready for those blessed boots
可怜的小子
Poor lad
不好意思
Excuse me
不是我干的
I didn't do it
能为你服务吗
Could I help you?
好  我要点餐
Yeah, I'm ready to order
要来点什么
What'll you have?
我要点
I'll take a
你说什么
What did you say?
我说我要点
I said I'll take a
我听到他点的菜了  蟹老板
I heard his order, Mr. Krabs
他说他要
He said he wants
什么
What?
还有
And a
什么
What?
吱吱吱
那不是我写的
I didn't write that
吱吱吱
谁说的
Who said that?
什么
What?
全世界最好的煎炸厨师能这样吗
Could the world's greatest fry cook do this?
还有这样
And this
别说了
Stop it
没听到吗
Don't you hear it?
对  是我干的
Yes, I did it
是我干的
I did it
我把靴子拿走了
I took the boots
靴子就在这地板底下
They're here under the floorboard
求你消停消停吧
Oh, please, make it stop
都是这丑的要命的靴子吱吱叫声害的
It's the squeaking of the hideous boots
对不起
I'm sorry
我再也受不了那个可恶的吱吱叫声了
but I can't take the infernal squeaking no more
事成了
The deed is done
你怎么在吃我靴子  蟹老板
Why did you eat my boots, Mr. Krabs?
因为小子  你用不着
Because, lad, you didn't need them
不是因为靴子  是因为贵重物品
It's not the boots, it's the bootee
我是说靴子背后的人
I mean the person in the boots
你是个很棒的煎炸厨师
You're a great fry cook
你真这么觉得吗  蟹老板
You really think so, Mr. Krabs?
真的  小子
I do, son
这是我欠你的工资
Here's your paycheck I owe you
外加奖金
plus a bonus
好吧  还是只给工资好了
Well, there's your paycheck anyway
我要休个假
I need a vacation
拜  蟹老板
Bye, Mr. Krabs
离开裤头村一周时间
A long week away from Bikini Bottom
正是我需要的
is exactly what I need
只有我还有我宝贝女儿  珍珍
just me and my darling daughter, Pearl
别忘了我的新脚蹼鞋  老爸
Don't forget my new flipper slippers, daddy
女儿  我不会忘的
Darling, I won't
不好了
Oh, no